Mohit Saini

779, Govindpuri, New Delhi, Delhi, India • Phone: +917983633312 • Email: mohitsaini035@gmail.com

PROFILE

Seasoned IT professional having close to 2.5 years of experience in IT infrastructure technologies. Highly motivated and dedicated individual with strong technical and problem-solving skills, interested in a full-time position where I could utilize my experience and add value to the company.

SKILLS

- System Admin
- Imaging
- · Packaging
- Deployments
- Patching
- IT Support
- Active directory
- · Group Policy
- Experience in Virtualized environments
- Azure
- SCCM

EXPERIENCE

MICROLAND LTD.

Gurgaon

10/2018 – present

Administrator

- Experience in patch deployment and software distribution through SCCM 2007 / 2012.
- Handled issue with Ubuntu, Mac and Windows users in the organization.
- Experience in SQL and executing SQL reporting from SCCM database.
- Experience with SCCM 2007/2012 OSD (Operating System Deployment), Microsoft patching and software deployments.
- To upgrade the available systems from windows 7 to windows 8.1 and office 2013 to office 2016 through SCCM.
- knowledge of SCCM client installation, software distribution, remote control, and other SCCM issues.
- Planning System Centre Configuration Manager hierarchy and site system roles creating and managing Boundary Groups across one or more Distribution Point.
- Knowledge of installation and configuration of SCCM central / CAS, Primary and Secondary Sites, WSUS / MDT Integration.
- Implementation Upgraded troubleshoot SQL installations and database for SCCM.
- knowledge of SQL Server and associated components and creating custom reports using SQL Queries and SQL report builder.
- Provided network administration to include LAN troubleshooting and resolution, more than 700 endusers with Desktop, Laptop, Printer and peripheral devices on-site support & remote support.
- Implement, manage and troubleshoot Active Directory and Group Policy Objects.
- Implement and troubleshoot Active Directory Federation Services (ADFS) and MFS.
- Implement and troubleshoot Azure AD connect.
- Experience in migrating all kinds of workloads from on-premises to Azure.

KAIZEN SERVICES PVT. LTD.

Gurgaon

04/2018 - 10/2018

IT Engineer

- Adding, removing, or updating user account information, reset passwords.
- Worked on Avamar Server for Data backup.
- Managing and Implementing Active directory, DHCP & DNS.
- Introducing and integrating new technologies into existing data center environments.
- Deployment operating system updates, patches, and configuration changes.
- Installation and configuration the Network Printers and scanners.
- Implementing & Managing Group policy.
- Performing routine audits of systems and software.

- Installing and configuring new hardware and software.
- Managing and maintaining McAfee Antivirus Servers and Live update server.

OLX INDIA PVT LTD

Gurgaon

08/2017 - 04/2018

IT Engineer

- Provided network administration to include LAN troubleshooting and resolution, more than 500 endusers with Desktop, Laptop, Printer and peripheral devices on-site support & remote support.
- Worked on ticketing tool such as JIRA & Service-Now.
- Solution for Network (LAN) which is based on workgroup & Domain environment using networking devices like Switches, Ethernet, Modem & Wi-Fi Router.
- Installed, configured, and maintained the functionality of company's desktop systems with peripheral appendages and software.
- Configuration the Cyberoam VPN in the UBUNTU, Windows & Mac user's Systems.
- Close customer technical issue with in SLA to avoid further escalation.
- Handled issue with Ubuntu, Mac and Windows users in the organization.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- B.TECH (CSE) with 66% from A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University (2015).
- 12th with 61% from UP Board (2011).
- 10th with 60% from UP Board (2009)

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name: Mohit Saini

Father's Name: Mr. Devendra Kumar

Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Single

Gender: Male

Language Known: Hindi, English, Punjabi

Permanent Address: Pushpanjali Vihar Janta Road Saharanpur-247001

DECLARATION

I consider myself familiar with software Aspects. I am also confident of my ability to team.	I hereby
declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my Knowledge.	-

Date:

Place:

Name: Mohit Saini